compare.com 2000-08-15

# MSN.COM Privacy Statement

The Internet is an amazing tool. It has the power to change the way we live, and we're starting to see that potential today. With only a few mouse-clicks, you can follow the news, look up facts, buy goods and services, and communicate with others from around the world--even people you might never have met. It's important to Microsoft to help its customers retain their privacy when they take advantage of all the Internet has to offer.

Microsoft is a member of TRUSTe, an independent, non-profit initiative that exists to help people such as yourself feel confident about using the Internet for your communication, shopping, research, and living. TRUSTe aims to build this confidence by promoting the principles of disclosure and fair information practices among the Web sites that participate in the program.

What this means to you is, we are committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful, safe, online experience that you can get anywhere.

Microsoft is a premier sponsor of TRUSTe and a member of the TRUSTe privacy program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit initiative whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting TRUSTe's principles of fair information practices.

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [MSNPrivacy@msn.com](mailto:MSNPrivacy@msn.com). If the Web site has not responded to your inquiry, or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, contact [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/users/watchdog.html).

**_Privacy Principles_**

Because your privacy is important to us, MSN sites displaying this privacy statement will operate by the following six principles. Users should additionally consult the Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) section accompanying this Privacy Statement for more information regarding these principles.

**Principle 1.**   
MSN sites will explicitly ask when they need information that personally identifies you or allows them to contact you ("Personally Identifiable Information"). Generally this information is requested when registering for a site, when requesting a particular service, or when entering a sweepstakes or contest. When possible, MSN sites will provide you with the means to make sure that your Personally Identifiable Information is correct and current.

**Principle 2.**   
MSN sites and their necessary service partners use your Personally Identifiable Information to operate the sites and services and to inform you of new features, services, and products from Microsoft and its affiliates. Some MSN sites may also carefully select other companies to send you information about their products or services which are related to the site's service but are not necessary to its operation (a "Secondary Use").

**Principle 3.**   
If an MSN site intends to use Personally Identifiable Information for a Secondary Use, the MSN site will provide you with instructions on how to decline this service. You may also stop the delivery of informational or promotional e-mail from MSN sites by following the instructions on the e-mail sent to you.

**Principle 4.**   
MSN Sites are primarily directed to online users ages 13 and above. For those MSN sites that require users to provide age information in order to access the site or to participate in the activities offered by the site, MSN will require users who indicate that they are under the age of 13 to get parental consent prior to using the site, by creating a Microsoft Kids Passport account, or the website will attempt to block their access to the site.

**Principle 5.**   
MSN sites may disclose Personally Identifiable Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Microsoft or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Microsoft, the site or the users of MSN, and (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Microsoft, MSN, the site or the public.

**Principle 6.**   
If at any time you believe that an MSN site has not adhered to these principles, please notify MSN by e-mail at [MSNPrivacy@msn.com ](mailto:MSNPrivacy@msn.com) and we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.

MSN is committed to maintaining its position as a premier site on the Internet. As our site continues to develop, we may add new services and features to our website. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Statement, this document will be updated appropriately.

For more information about our Privacy Statement, see the following **Frequently Asked Questions** or the FAQs accompanying the MSN sites.

**_Frequently Asked Questions_**

[How will users know which privacy statement applies to their personal information?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ2)

[Do all sites on MSN need Personally Identifiable Information?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ5)

[How do MSN sites collect the Personally Identifiable Information?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ6)

[Does that mean MSN sites sell my Personally Identifiable Information to other companies?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ9)

[What if I do not want my Personally Identifiable Information shared with another company?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ10)

[What about companies that partner with MSN sites to provide the products or services on a site?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ11)

[What about the privacy of Personally Identifiable Information collected from users under the age of 13?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ12)

[Do MSN sites collect other forms of information about its users?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ13)

[How do I correct or change Personally Identifiable Information that I have given to an MSN site?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ14)

[Is my Personally Identifiable Information secure from others using the MSN site?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ15)

[How else might someone learn of my Personally Identifiable Information while visiting an MSN site?](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#FAQ16)

_Do all sites on MSN follow these privacy principles?_

MSN is made up of many sites, and new ones are added all the time. At this time, the MSN privacy statement applies to those sites which display this statement in conjunction with the privacy notice on the site's Web pages. While MSN encourages other site operators on MSN to comply with these principles, users should carefully examine the privacy statements of sites appearing on or linking to or from MSN which do not display this statement. Personal Information that you choose to provide to other sites will be subject to the privacy policies of that Web site.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_How will users know which privacy statement applies to their Personally Identifiable Information?_

Pages throughout MSN display a "Privacy Statement" link which identifies the privacy statement applying to the site. Users may click on the link at any time to read the applicable privacy statement. MSN Websites can be identified by the MSN logo appearing in the top left-hand corner of the screen.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_Why is TRUSTe so important?_

TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence on the Internet. Businesses that display the TRUSTe logo have agreed to privacy principles developed by TRUSTe and to periodic reviews to make sure that the businesses' privacy practices are in keeping with the policies. In the event TRUSTe learns of serious violations of a businesses' privacy practices, TRUSTe takes steps to insure compliance. Microsoft strongly believes in the TRUSTe mission and is a premier sponsor of the organization.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_Does Microsoft belong to any other privacy organizations?_

Microsoft has taken a leadership position on privacy, working closely with both policy and technology organizations to create standards and best practices for putting people in control of their Personal Information online. Amongst others, Microsoft is a member of TRUSTe, the Online Privacy Alliance and the P3P Working Group at the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) and international organizations working on these issues.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_Do all sites on MSN need Personally Identifiable Information?_

No, for many MSN sites it is not necessary for you to provide any information in order for them to provide their services. In other instances, the MSN site may request minimal information, such as your ZIP code, in order to personalize the site. ZIP codes allow the site to provide targeted services, such as the local news or weather, but do not provide the site with any information regarding who you are or how to contact you. Other MSN sites need more information about you in order to operate their service. For example, CarPoint needs your name and other contact information in order to allow its service partners to respond to your request for more information about a particular vehicle.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_How do MSN sites collect Personally Identifiable Information?_

Personally Identifiable Information is collected by specifically requesting it from you. Generally this occurs when you register at a site, request a service, or enter an online contest or sweepstakes.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_What about "Cookies"?_

"Cookies" are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. "Cookies" can make the Web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site, such as your preferred chart settings for MSN Encarta. The use of "Cookies" is an industry standard, and many major Web sites use them to provide useful features for their customers. "Cookies" in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are initially set to accept "Cookies". If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse "Cookies". However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a Web site if you do so. For example, the subscription services of MSN Encarta may only be accessed if you accept "Cookies".To learn more about cookies, click here for the [MSN Personal Information Center](http://update.msn.com/profilemgmt/).

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_How do MSN sites use Personally Identifiable Information?_

Usually, MSN sites and their necessary service partners use your Personally Identifiable Information to operate the site and to deliver their services. For example, if you are using MSN HomeAdvisor, a completed mortgage application may at your request be forwarded to potential lenders. MSN sites also use your Personally Identifiable Information to inform you of other products or services available from Microsoft and its affiliates. Some MSN sites also use Personally Identifiable Information to allow other companies to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you (Secondary Uses). If an MSN site proposes to use Personally Identifiable Information for Secondary Uses, you will be provided an opportunity to instruct the MSN site to not allow such contact. You may also check the ["MSN Personal Information Center"](http://update.msn.com/profilemgmt/) to view, edit, or delete your information. This new service allows you to delete your personal information from MSN's database. Not all sites are represented at the Center today. Keep checking as we add more MSN sites and services to the Center in the near future.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_Does that mean MSN sites sell my Personally Identifiable Information to other companies?_

No, MSN does not sell customer lists. However, individual MSN sites may partner with businesses to provide special services to our customers. This type of use of Personally Identifiable Information is called a "Secondary Use" because it is not necessary to the operation of the business or site. For example, a site may offer discount coupons for services or related products. In many cases these discounts would be an added benefit to our customers.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_What if I do not want my Personally Identifiable Information shared with another company?_

If an MSN site proposes to make a Secondary Use of your Personally Identifiable Information, the MSN site will provide you with instructions on how to decline this service. You may also stop the delivery of future informational or promotional mail from MSN sites by following the instructions on the mail sent to you. In addition, you may visit the ["MSN Personal Information Center"](http://update.msn.com/profilemgmt/) to view, edit or delete your personal information from the MSN database. Not all sites are represented at this time; we will be adding more MSN sites and services to the Center in the near future.

_What about companies that partner with MSN sites to provide the site's products or services?_

An MSN site may have several necessary service partners who assist in providing the service or product associated with the site. As part of the operations of the site, these companies may have access to your Personally Identifiable Information. These companies may provide routine services, such as credit card processing, or may provide essential elements of the site. For example, MSN CarPoint must provide contact information to automotive dealers in order to respond to specific requests made by customers. Without this relationship MSN CarPoint could not provide its service to you. These uses of Personally Identifiable Information are primary to the operation of the site and are not considered Secondary Uses.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_What about the privacy of Personally Identifiable Information collected from users under the age of 13?_

Safeguarding the Personally Identifiable Information of our online users under the age of 13 is extremely important. For those MSN sites where users have indicated they are under the age of 13, MSN will require parental consent for their child to use the website or the services it offers. Microsoft Kids Passport allows parents to consent to the collection, use and sharing of their children's information with Microsoft and the sites and services operated by or for Microsoft (including MSN). MSN sites will collect the minimum amount of Personally Identifiable Information necessary to the operation of the service. [Click here](http://www.passport.com/consumer/privacypolicy.asp?PPlcid=1033#kids) to view the Microsoft Kids Passport website and Privacy Statement.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_Do MSN sites collect other forms of information about its users?_

In addition to the use of Personally Identifiable Information to operate MSN sites, an MSN site may also gather anonymous information, which may be used by Microsoft or shared with third parties. This is information which does not personally identify you, but which may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer. For example, MSN might tell its advertisers how many users visited a particular advertisement, and for how long, so they can measure whether the advertisement was effective. This information is also used to generate advertising rates. Generally this information is collected through "traffic data" and may entail the use of "Cookies," "IP addresses," or other numeric codes used to identify a computer.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_How do I correct or change Personally Identifiable Information that I have given to an MSN site?_

Some MSN sites operate registration pages that allow you to review and update the Personally Identifiable Information you have submitted. Elsewhere, you are simply given the option of unsubscribing to the service for which you signed up. In all other cases where you need to correct Personally Identifiable Information you have submitted to an MSN site, please contact the service address published by the particular MSN site.

In addition, MSN has created a new feature, the MSN Personal Information Center. There you may choose to edit your personally identifiable information at certain MSN sites. Not all sites are represented at this time; we will be adding more MSN sites and services to the Center in the near future. Click here to view the [Center](http://update.msn.com/profilemgmt/).

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_Is my Personally Identifiable Information secure from others using the MSN site?_

Personally Identifiable Information collected by MSN sites is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. In many instances, such as in the case of credit card numbers, the Personally Identifiable Information is encrypted before you conduct your transaction.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

_How else might someone learn of my Personally Identifiable Information while visiting an MSN site?_

In addition to directly providing information to an MSN site, you might also provide Personally Identifiable Information through chat sessions, e-mail exchanges or newsgroups made available to you on MSN. The Statement of Privacy does not cover this type of transfer of your Personally Identifiable Information. You should always be careful when distributing your Personally Identifiable Information in this manner. And remember that online chat sessions and newsgroup use is considered public and you are responsible for your actions in these areas.

[[Back]](http://www.msn.com/help/legal/privacy.htm#back)

Updated April 2000
